<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:atom='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
<channel>
<atom:link href='http://dragsubil.github.io/' rel='self' type='application/rss+xml'/>
<title>
S.Pa.M.
</title>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/
</link>
<description>
Powered by Anthropomorphic Monkeys
</description>
<lastBuildDate>
Sat, 25 Feb 2017 19:55:14 +0530
</lastBuildDate>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2017-02-25-do-they-have-control/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2017-02-25-do-they-have-control/
</link>
<title>
Do They Have Control?
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I've had this thought in my head. A question, really. And I don't know if there is or will be any answer for it. Maybe you can answer it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But before I can ask the question to you, I need to set up some background. Get you to understand where I'm coming from. And so, here's a blog post in three acts. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;act&amp;#95;1:&amp;#95;a&amp;#95;hundred&amp;#95;different&amp;#95;hooks&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Act 1: A Hundred Different Hooks&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unless you're a hermit who has spent the last twenty years in the Himalayas (in which case: Welcome to the new world! Trump is the US President), then you've probably used Facebook and Google. You may also be aware, at least vaguely, about how they track the activity of their users. Maybe you don't know how deep this privacy rabbit hole goes. Or maybe you do, and either think it's a fair trade off for the services they offer. Or maybe you're one of the super paranoid ones that encrypt everything and browse only through &lt;a href='ttps://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html'&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt;. Or you might be like me, standing somewhere in between.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whichever way you swing, it is a plain and simple fact that these days, privacy on the internet takes some effort to achieve. Here's a quick and dirty primer on some of the things that Google and Facebook do:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Like buttons in websites send information back to Facebook even if you don't click. &lt;a href='ttps://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424052748704281504576329441432995616'&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='ttps://www.technologyreview.com/s/541351/facebooks-like-buttons-will-soon-track-your-web-browsing-to-target-ads/'&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='ttp://www.geek.com/news/facebook-like-button-tracks-you-even-if-you-dont-click-1380793/'&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Facebook analyzes not only what you do, but also &lt;a href='ttps://arstechnica.com/business/2013/12/facebook-collects-conducts-research-on-status-updates-you-never-post/'&gt;what you don't do&lt;/a&gt;. They can    extrapolate a lot of information about you from what you clicked and didn't    click.    (Facebook be like: *This guy hesitates when he sees pictures of food and    then scrolls away. He must be on a diet. Let's bombard him with ads of diet    supplements.*)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='ttps://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_and_privacy_issues'&gt;I don't know if you realize this but Google knows everything&lt;/a&gt;. And I mean EVERYTHING!    Every time you do a Google search, or use Google maps, or Gmail, or Drive,    or Youtube, or download an app from the Play Store, you are basically handing over    information about you, which they then turn around and use to sell ads.    &lt;a href='ttps://twitter.com/grady_booch/status/808324380119994368?lang=en'&gt;Google is an advertising company with a bunch of hobbies&lt;/a&gt;. It's their    bread and butter.    (You think you're clever because you browse porn logged out on a private tab, but its not a far cry to    imagine that Google can still connect your late night fetish searches to your profile) &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is just a small sampling. I encourage you to do your own research. And it's not just Google and Facebook.  Uber tracks your location &lt;a href='ttp://www.npr.org/sections/alltechconsidered/2016/12/01/503985473/uber-now-tracks-passengers-locations-even-after-theyre-dropped-off'&gt;for five minutes after your ride is done&lt;/a&gt;.  So Uber now gets to know where you're going even if you were dropped off elsewhere. Windows 10, by default, &lt;a href='ttps://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2015/08/windows-10-doesnt-offer-much-privacy-by-default-heres-how-to-fix-it/'&gt;is set to share huge amounts of information to Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;. The list goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And there's very little we can do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Services like these are ubiquitous. They form a central part of today's world and they won't be giving up their positions anytime soon. And many people &lt;i&gt;wouldn't want them to&lt;/i&gt; either. Imagine if Google or Facebook or Amazon disappeared tomorrow. Try imagining living without the instant access to knowledge that Google provides, without the instant access to our friends and family that Facebook provides.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;But there are free-as-in-freedom alternatives&quot;, the hardcore among you will be saying. But do you think the alternatives can provide the sheer &lt;i&gt;convenience&lt;/i&gt; that these services  offer to the common user? All these companies have their hooks sunk deep in all of us with no intention  of letting go. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And for many of us, these are acceptable tradeoffs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fact is: these services are super useful. Google and Facebook and others like it are world changing. Instant access to almost any information! Instant contact to almost any person anywhere, anytime! And you never needed to pay a dime! All this technology would've been wild science fiction to the average person 30 or 40 years ago. But we have it now. And all it costs is our data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And we chose to pay it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;act&amp;#95;2:&amp;#95;we&amp;#95;made&amp;#95;our&amp;#95;choices&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Act 2: We Made Our Choices&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've had a Facebook account since December 2009 and got a Gmail account a little later. If you count &lt;a href='http://www.gaiaonline.com/'&gt;Gaia Online&lt;/a&gt;, I've had access to social media since late 2008. Point being, I've been here a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And in the early days, I was all in when it came to the social media game. I wrote status updates, uploaded photos, liked pages, commented on other people's photos and statuses, the whole nine yards. And I enjoyed it, as unsociable as I was. I didn't know or care about privacy issues at the time. Few of us did. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It wasn't Facebook's fault that I put all that information out there. They provided a nice platform for me to use and I chose to use it.  Everything I did was of my own free will.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As much as I dislike and disagree with Facebook's practices, I understand that they are a business first. They have an obligation to their shareholders and are simply trying to make the most out of a userbase of nearly 2 billion people, who are willingly putting their details out in public. The targeted advertising model keeps everyone happy. The shareholders are happy because the money keeps rolling in from the advertisers. The advertisers are happy because they get better results thanks to targeting. The users are happy because they can continue to use Facebook for free. Facebook is happy because they can continue to collect more information to target ads to the users and make more money because the users keeping using it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Facebook decided to give up their data collection and targeted advertising and be good guys and they choose to go for a subscription model where the users pay to keep the site running, 99.99% of the users or more would just pack up and leave. Facebook would crumble.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We, the users, as a collective decided early on that we wanted a Web where we don't have to pay to access any website. We, the users, also chose to give our information to Facebook and Google and the rest. They never forced us. We gave it to them of our own free will. It was our choices that led to the advertiser driven, data collecting, user specific targeting model that we have today. We chose to give away our information freely. We chose to accept our information being collected as a fair price for a free internet. Maybe we didn't realize what we were doing. We just liked free stuff, not really understanding what that cost us. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm not saying that the free internet that we have is a bad thing. Hell no! It's fantastic. I wouldn't be where I am now if Google had a subscription fee. I am simply pointing out that the free internet has forced websites to look for alternate means of making money to get some return for their work. Whatever they end up doing with our data, we only have ourselves to blame for giving it to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;act&amp;#95;3:&amp;#95;do&amp;#95;they&amp;#95;have&amp;#95;control?&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Act 3: Do they have control?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't really have a point to make here. I only want to ask one question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Do the children have control over their data?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you have children of your own, age 10,11ish or less? Children without the requisite skills to use the internet beyond a few mobile apps? What about young siblings? Or nieces and nephews? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm willing to bet you or someone else have taken pictures of them and put them up on Facebook. Maybe tagged their names on those photos, identifying them. Heck, they might even have Facebook accounts in their name managed by the parents.  And even if you or anyone you know have never done this, you've probably seen it on your Facebook feed. Proud parents, with the help of the rest of the family, documenting almost every aspect of their young one's lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've had access to social media for close to 40 percent of my life. That's a lot. But there are children now who weren't alive when Facebook came into being. And many of them have their lives up on display online for the whole world to see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Facebook and Google and the rest to analyze and sell to the highest bidder. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And they were never given a choice in the matter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If today's children grow up and decide that they do not want their whole life to be lying around on the internet, do you think Facebook and Friends would just shrug and say &quot;Okay, cool, whatever&quot;? We are living in an unprecedented time, with data being collected right from the womb and beyond. Data like that is invaluable for those who profit off it. They wouldn't want to give away their gold mine. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At least when parts of my life go online, I know &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; am making that decision. No one made it for me. I have always had full control. But what about the children of today? Do parents ask their permission before uploading a photo or a video of them? Can the children understand the nuances of privacy on the internet and carefully choose to grant or deny consent? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Children have a right to choose what happens with their data. If they are too young to choose then it is the responsibility of the legal guardian to take those actions that guarantee that the children get maximum control over their data when they are finally old enough to choose for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I ask again: The children in your life... &lt;strong&gt;do they have control?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Sat, 25 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2017-01-07-useless-blog-02/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2017-01-07-useless-blog-02/
</link>
<title>
Useless Blog #2
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happy New Year everybody!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes I know I'm a week late. Sue me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What a week its been! I attended my very first, &quot;real hackers don't sleep&quot;, 2 day hackathon! I got sick at my very first, &quot;real hackers don't sleep&quot;, 2 day hackathon! I threw up at my very first, &quot;real hackers don't sleep&quot;, 2 day hackathon! And then I swore that I would never again attend any &quot;real hackers don't sleep&quot;, 2 day hackathons ever again! You &quot;real hackers&quot; can keep your nights, I prefer daylight and 8 hours in a warm bed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What else happened this week? Oh yes, I decided to learn Emacs. From scratch. For  some inexplicable reason. None of that SpacEmacs stuff, no sir! I happen to like putting myself through immense pain. Masochist, you say? I don't know what you're  talking about. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This of course lead to me deciding I need the latest and greatest to start my journey: Emacs 25.1! It's not available via my package manager so decided to do the next best thing: compile from source. But of course this happens&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Makefile:736: recipe for target 'bootstrap-Emacs' failed
make&amp;#91;1&amp;#93;: &amp;#42;&amp;#42;&amp;#42; &amp;#91;bootstrap-Emacs&amp;#93; Segmentation fault &amp;#40;core dumped&amp;#41;
make&amp;#91;1&amp;#93;: Leaving directory '/home/subil/Downloads/Emacs-25.1/src'
Makefile:398: recipe for target 'src' failed
make: &amp;#42;&amp;#42;&amp;#42; &amp;#91;src&amp;#93; Error 2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well ain't that -ucking swell!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I'm making do with Emacs 24 until Ubuntu gets its shit together and makes Emacs 25 available. Or I switch to &lt;a href='ttps://www.archlinux.org/'&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt; or something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But Subil, weren't you using Vim?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still will be. I'll be using Emacs with a vim bindings plugin anyway (once I figure out how to install the bloody thing). On the bright side, I'm finally going to watch the Doctor Who Christmas Special so that's something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vim fanatics mob: We found the heretic! &lt;b&gt;KILL HIM!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yikes! Gotta run!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-19-books-read/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-19-books-read/
</link>
<title>
Books I've read this past week
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;I'M BACK BOIIII!!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Man it's good to have internet again! That storm did a number on my city but we're getting back up now. In order to keep my brain from oozing out  from sheer boredom during the day,  I've been doing nothing but reading this past week. Thought I'd share my opinions on a couple of books in this comeback post. Here we go!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Note: None of the books below are programming or tech related. If that's what you're looking for, you'll have to go elsewhere).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Arcanum Unbounded - Brandon Sanderson&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28595941-arcanum-unbounded'&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1466536615l/28595941.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arcanum Unbounded is a short story/novella collection set in Brandon Sanderson's Cosmere universe. All in all its a great read for a fanboy like myself but I wouldn't recommend it to a newcomer to the author's works as some of the stories require at least some familiarity with his other Cosmere novels. There's only one exclusive story in the book (Edgedancer), all the other ones were already available in one form or another. But Edgedancer alone is worth the price of admission. Seriously, Lift is now my favorite character and I'm disappointed that she won't appear as a POV character in the main Stormlight Archive series  (the story sequence to which Edgedancer belongs to) till much later. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'd recommend picking it up if you're as invested in this universe as I am. It's even got maps of the various solar systems in which the different stories are set!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Coraline - Neil Gaiman&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17061.Coraline'&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1443798739l/17061.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What to say about Coraline? It is ostensibly a children's book but don't let that label stop you. I'm not much of a critical reader so all I can articulate is that there is a certain &lt;i&gt;something&lt;/i&gt; about this book that really reels you in. It follows the eponymous character Coraline, a little girl who just moved to a new house and stumbles onto a sinister alternate world behind a locked door. Neil Gaiman really captures the eerie atmosphere in his writing. It's a short read but it is a really rich and beautiful one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that's it (I did say 'a couple of books'). This post was a bit rushed but I wanted to get something out as a celebration of getting my internet connection back. I'm giving a talk at my local Python meetup later this week so I have to do  some research and prepare and shit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So long!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Slides for my talk can be found &lt;a href='https://github.com/dragsubil/talks/tree/master/2016-12-24%20obscure%20python%20implementations'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Mon, 19 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-10-botwhothanksbots/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-10-botwhothanksbots/
</link>
<title>
Thanking the Reddit bots for their hard work
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;You know, I was supposed to be learning &lt;a href='http://www.sqlalchemy.org/'&gt;SQLAlchemy&lt;/a&gt; in the hopes adding  something employable my resume (all I have right now is 'knows some python'). But I end up messing around on reddit instead. &lt;em&gt;Sigh&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, if you've used reddit for any length of time, you've probably noticed a few bot accounts. They're usually there to perform some tasks on behalf of the humans. &lt;a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/AutoModerator/'&gt;Automoderator&lt;/a&gt; is ubiquitous throughout reddit. &lt;a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/remindmebot'&gt;RemindMeBot&lt;/a&gt; can be called on demand to set a reminder for yourself by calling for it in  the comments or via PM. Those are just a couple of the many throughout  reddit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite their status as automated servants, bots deserve some gratitude too. (If you're one to disagree, we'll see how much mercy the machines will have for you when Skynet takes over the world). So I wrote a bot that thanks other bots on reddit (the machines won't have any mercy for me either, since I'm &lt;del&gt;enslaving&lt;/del&gt; creating a bot to do the thanking).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to write a reddit bot in python is by using the &lt;a href='https://github.com/praw-dev/praw'&gt;Python Reddit API Wrapper&lt;/a&gt;, PRAW for short. In the interest of avoiding writing  redundant information, you should atleast read the &lt;a href='https://praw.readthedocs.io/en/latest/getting_started/quick_start.html'&gt;quickstart&lt;/a&gt; in the  PRAW docs. (This blog was written for v4.0 of PRAW, so if you have an older version it won't work).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bot works by iterating through a list of bot usernames over and over at the rate of one bot thanked every 10 minutes. The 10 minute timeout is  because reddit doesn't allow an account to post on a subreddit more than once within that time period unless the account is an active participant. Here's what the loop looks like:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;python&quot;&gt;
botlist = &amp;#91;'RemindMeBot', 'AutoModerator', 'TotesMessenger', 'samacharbot2'&amp;#93;

for botname in botlist:

    reddit = praw.Reddit&amp;#40;'thankerbot'&amp;#41;
    bot&amp;#95;object = reddit.redditor&amp;#40;botname&amp;#41;
    bot&amp;#95;new&amp;#95;submissions = bot&amp;#95;object.new&amp;#40;limit=1&amp;#41;

    for submission in bot&amp;#95;new&amp;#95;submissions:
        # Checking if the submission is a comment we can reply to
        if isinstance&amp;#40;submission, praw.models.reddit.comment.Comment&amp;#41;:
            post&amp;#95;reply&amp;#40;botname, submission&amp;#41;
            time.sleep&amp;#40;600&amp;#41; # waiting 10 minutes 
                            # because reddit doesn't want spam

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having created &lt;code&gt;reddit&lt;/code&gt; as our user agent, we now create a &lt;code&gt;Reddit.redditor&lt;/code&gt; object to represent the bot we are going to send our thank you message. You'll notice that our user agent is initialized with only one argument. This is because I've already set up a &lt;code&gt;praw.ini&lt;/code&gt; file that contains the rest of the information (Instructions &lt;a href='https://praw.readthedocs.io/en/latest/getting_started/configuration/prawini.html'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We now retrieve their latest submissions with &lt;code&gt;bot&amp;#95;object.new&amp;#40;limit=x&amp;#41;&lt;/code&gt;, where &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; is the number of posts we want. Since we pass &lt;code&gt;limit=1&lt;/code&gt;, we only get their latest post. This returns a generator object that we can iterate through. Each submission is then checked to see if it is a &lt;code&gt;Comment&lt;/code&gt; object in order for our bot to reply to it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;code&gt;post&amp;#95;reply&amp;#40;&amp;#41;&lt;/code&gt; function looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;python&quot;&gt;
comment&amp;#95;string = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;
Thank you {}!
----

&amp;#94;&amp;#40;Because bots deserve gratitude.&amp;#41;
&amp;#91;Report an issue&amp;#93;&amp;#40;https://github.com/dragsubil/botWhoThanksBots/issues&amp;#41;

&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;

def post&amp;#95;reply&amp;#40;botname, comment&amp;#41;:
    try:
       comment.reply&amp;#40;comment&amp;#95;string.format&amp;#40;botname&amp;#41;&amp;#41;
    except Exception as e:
        print&amp;#40;&amp;quot;Moving to the next bot because exception occured:&amp;quot;, str&amp;#40;e&amp;#41;&amp;#41;
        return

    print&amp;#40;&amp;quot;Thanked {}. id: {}&amp;quot;.format&amp;#40;botname, comment.id&amp;#41;&amp;#41;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;We try to thank the bot by calling the &lt;code&gt;reply&lt;/code&gt; function on our comment object. Sometimes you might get an APIException because reddit couldn't process our request for some reason but we handle it and keep chugging  away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that's pretty much it. You can find the code &lt;a href='https://github.com/dragsubil/botWhoThanksBots'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and you can say  hello to &lt;a href='https://www.reddit.com/user/botWhoThanksBots/'&gt;/u/botWhoThanksBots&lt;/a&gt; on Reddit. Though I don't know how long I'll keep it active. It's already been banned from 4 subreddits, so who knows what will happen!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-07-the-monster-sneaks-up/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-07-the-monster-sneaks-up/
</link>
<title>
The monster that sneaks up on you
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I realize that the posting schedule has gone to whack but that last post was  too long to finish in one day. And so I decided I could skip a day as a reward (not that I dislike writing these, mind! But I didn't want to overextend myself). Also I realize this is not necessarily a technical post but it is something I need  to address, for my own sake. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was of the opinion that if you were aware of or had read about a situation before,  you could identify it immediately when it occurred to you and you could be prepared to handle it.  (This doesn't apply for every situation, of course. No amount of reading could suitably prepare you for, say, being dropped in front a herd of hungry velociraptors). Turns out I wasn't entirely right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's the holidays for me right now and a friend of mine invited me develop an Android app with him. I thought &quot;Hey! Why not!&quot; and said yes, despite knowing zilch about app development. I thought I could learn as I go along. This was a week ago and I haven't much much progress. Whereas my friend has already started work on the app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another friend of mine has started to learn Python. He'd been putting it off for quite a while but is now blazing through it. Far faster than my sorry ass did when I started (It took four years before I wrote my first Python application). This guy is also a Javascript ace, wrote a &lt;a href='http://babble.gq/'&gt;chat app&lt;/a&gt; that's actually been seen and appreciated by other people, and can pull all-nighters without turning into a zombie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And so the doubts started to creep in. &quot;Am I doing enough?&quot; &quot;Is there more I could be learning?&quot; &quot;Am I making the most of my day?&quot; and on and on. It wasn't just seeing my friends that brought this on. It's a whole host of things that builds up overtime. Seeing other people do cool shit while I sit here doing comparatively nothing. There are twelve year olds with a dozen apps  in the app stores and its not just their grandma who is using them. What the heck have I done with  my life? A couple of silly Python scripts? This dumb blog that a grand total of two people, including myself, read? What?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Say hello to the monster. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That feeling of inadequacy that every programmer goes through at least once in their lifetime. The feeling that everyone in this business is way smarter and more talented than you are. That no matter how much you try, how much you try to learn, you can never keep up with everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;...and that's okay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No, really! It's okay to feel that way. I'd read about it a lot and thought I was prepared. But it still caught me. It catches everyone. There's no escaping it. There's always going to be more to learn no matter how much you try. There's always going to be folks smarter than you. So don't stress yourself over what everyone else has done. Do what's best for you! Don't burn yourself out trying to do everything. Programming isn't  fun or productive if you don't allow yourself time to just chill out. If all you ever do is compete with everyone else over who has the most knowledge, or knows the most frameworks, or writes code in the  most languages, programming won't be fun anymore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heck! Don't take my word for it. I'm just some random bonehead who spends too much time on Reddit. Take &lt;a href='https://blog.codinghorror.com/keeping-up-and-just-in-time-learning/'&gt;Jeff Atwood's word&lt;/a&gt; instead. Or take the word of dozens of people who've talked about  &lt;a href='https://www.google.com/search?#hl=en&amp;q=imposter+syndrome'&gt;Imposter Syndrome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blog post is addressed from the me of the now to the me of the future (and also to my buddy the  Javascript ace, who tends to feel this way from time to time (Hey there pal!)). Because this probably won't be the last time you feel this way. We all feel inadequate sometimes, even the smartypants. That doesn't mean you're not doing enough. You're doing fine, mate! You're &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; doing comparatively nothing. You're doing a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; more than your than your stupid brain thinks. Just as long as you keep moving  forward and don't become complacent, that's plenty enough. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-04-ordovim/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-04-ordovim/
</link>
<title>
Ordovim or: How to half ass something with (predictably) crappy results
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; Neal Stephenson's books. He is the God Uncle of cyberpunk (the God&lt;em&gt;father&lt;/em&gt; of cyberpunk is, of course, William Gibson). One of Stephenson's doorstoppers is Cryptonomicon, a MASSIVE, 1100+ page monstrosity jam packed with everything you could want in a historical fiction/sorta cyberpunk novel. It's got action, World War II code breaking, guest appearances by Alan Turing, digressions on cryptography, a few predictions about the future (internet banking being one of them. Remember, it was published in 1999) and a ton of other things I can't remember. It even had graphs. &lt;em&gt;GRAPHS&lt;/em&gt; for duck's sake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, one of the things I remembered reading about in the book is Ordoemacs. Ordoemacs is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; text editor for the paranoid. Everything written in Ordoemacs is automatically encrypted when written to disk. At least, that's how I remembered it. So I wanted to do something similar, but in Vim. Thus, Ordovim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(See that 'half ass' in the title? Start counting them).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing a text editor from scratch is hard, really hard. Especially one with as much power as Vim. So I chose not to bother. A Vim plugin would've been easier. (This was my first, but understandable and sane, half ass. I'm nothing if not pragmatic).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;But I have to learn Vimscript to write a plugin. And Vimscript is &lt;em&gt;stoopid&lt;/em&gt;! Ugh!&quot;, I whined internally. Vimscript is powerful, no doubt! I mean, just look at all the &lt;a href='http://vimawesome.com/'&gt;plugins&lt;/a&gt; available. They're pretty rad. But my lazy bum didn't want to take the time to sit down and fully learn this kinda ugly language (&lt;a href='http://spacemacs.org/'&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/a&gt; and Elisp's distant siren song isn't helping either). So I decided to learn just enough to help me write this thing. But I soon found out plugins require a greater investment in time and learning  than I was inclined to give. So I reduced the requirement from a plugin to a function and a couple of autocommands. (This was my second half ass. Seeing a trend?).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;But you couldn't possibly do proper encryption with a single function.&quot; I hear you say. And you're right. Also I knew diddly squat about cryptography. Still don't, unless you call importing and using a Python library as sufficient cryptographic expertise. And that's exactly what I did. &lt;a href='https://github.com/andrewcooke/simple-crypt'&gt;Simple Crypt&lt;/a&gt; is a wrapper around a much more complex and powerful Python library called &lt;a href='https://www.dlitz.net/software/pycrypto/'&gt;PyCrypto&lt;/a&gt;. It's a kiddie fence created to protect knuckleheads like me from hurting myself trying  to climb the metaphorical jungle gym. It is dead simple to use. And gave me an easy way out from having to actually learn some cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;python&quot;&gt;from simplecrypt import encrypt, decrypt

plain&amp;#95;string = &amp;quot;This do be a string. Fortune prick me if it is not&amp;quot;
password = &amp;quot;yourpassword&amp;quot;

encrypted&amp;#95;string = encrypt&amp;#40;password, plain&amp;#95;string.encode&amp;#40;'UTF-8'&amp;#41;&amp;#41;
decrypted&amp;#95;string = decrypt&amp;#40;password, encrypted&amp;#95;string.decode&amp;#40;'UTF-8'&amp;#41;&amp;#41;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is literally that easy to use. I needed to do nothing else. Ask me what SHA1 stands for and you'll just get a blank stare. I wrote a dead simple python script with an easy to use encryption library and added a few lines to my vimrc to call that script whenever I opened a file with the extension &lt;code&gt;.ordo.enc&lt;/code&gt; (to decrypt it) or closed a file with the extension &lt;code&gt;.ordo&lt;/code&gt; (to encrypt it). (Half ass numero très).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The end result? It's... working? Sort of? Opening an encrypted file automatically decrypts it. But half asses strike back! You can't close the file or delete the buffer and expect that it will encrypt. Whichever buffer your '*.ordo' file is, only the file in the current buffer gets encrypted. You have to switch to the buffer of the file you want to encrypt before closing it. But hey! It's working. Right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Well that was a fun project!&quot;, I thought in my elation upon completion. &quot;Not half bad!&quot; You know how children can sit in a cardboard box and pretend they're piloting a spaceship. That was me, thinking I'd just made a working clone of Ordoemacs with some tape and a couple of screws. A true MacGyver is me. And so in the spirit of things, I decided to read that part in Cryptonomicon where they talk about Ordoemacs again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recall that I mentioned at the beginning this phrase: 'Alteast, that's how I &lt;em&gt;remembered&lt;/em&gt; it.' See that added emphasis on 'remembered'? Yeah. I've been going by memory all this time about how Ordoemacs actually worked. I hadn't opened that book in quite a while. Here's the quote from the book:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; OrdoEmacs, on the other hand, works exactly like regular Emacs, except that it encrypts everything before writing it out to disk. At no time is plaintext ever laid down on a disk by OrdoEmacs&amp;ndash;the only place it exists in its plain, readable form is in the pixels on the screen, and in the volatile RAM of the computer, whence it vanishes the moment power is shut down. Not only that, but it's coupled to a screensaver that uses the little built-in CCD camera in the laptop to check to see if you are actually there. It can't recognize your face, but it can tell whether or not a vaguely human-shaped form is sitting in front of it, and if that vaguely human-shaped form goes away, even for a fraction of a second, it will drop into a screen-saver that will blank the display and freeze the machine until such time as you type in a password, or biometrically verify your identity through voice recognition. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's.. well.. that's definitely not what I created.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here was my biggest half ass of them all. My halfiest ass, if you will. I never bothered to look at what Ordoemacs actually did before I set out to write &quot;Ordovim&quot;. Let's look at them one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; the only place it exists in its plain, readable form is in the pixels on the screen, and in the volatile RAM of the computer &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yeah, no. My &quot;Ordovim&quot; actually writes to disc first before encrypting and deleting the old plaintext file (which can easily be recovered).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; coupled to a screensaver &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; uses the little built-in CCD camera in the laptop to check to see if you are actually there &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; blank the display and freeze the machine until such time as you type in a password, or biometrically verify your identity through voice recognition. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nopity nopity nope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Ordovim&quot;, besides the fact that it does encryption, isn't even in the same galaxy as Ordoemacs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what was the takeaway here? Some of the things I learned at the end of this ordeal, which should be obvious to anyone with three quarters of a brain:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don't half ass things, because half asses multiply (I'm at sixteenth ass now).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Read the spec or you end up with &quot;Ordovim&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Invest a little bit of time to learning how to use and improve your skills with your tools (even if you think they are 'stoopid').&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Kiddie fences are nice, but you have to grow up sometime.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh! And go read Neal Stephenson books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find Ordovim &lt;a href='https://github.com/dragsubil/Ordovim'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Sun, 04 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-01-useless-blog-01/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-01-useless-blog-01/
</link>
<title>
Useless Blog #1
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh hey. You're back. I didn't think you'd write another post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yeah, well, I said I would, didn't I? So here I am. But it's not like I have  anything interesting to say though. I thought I would learn enough in two days to write something interesting. But the most interesting thing I did that I have any coherent thoughts about is that I shaved my head.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sigh&lt;/em&gt; I want to write but at the same time I don't want to fill this blog up with rambling crap (unless its entertaining crap). On the bright side, Christmas is only 25 days away (woo!). But college starts the day after (boo!). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had planned that this blog would be more of a stream of consciousness thing but that doesn't work really well if your stream of consciousness isn't very interesting. So for the next blog I'll least get a topic knocking around in my head before I sit down and write something. Hey, I'm actually starting to get ideas as I type this. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So are you going to rewrite this post?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No. I'm lazy. And this post isn't &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; bad. I'll leave it here. Like, y'know, legacy code!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But legacy code is generally not a good thing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And you're an imaginary rubber duck constructed and maintained by my mind to serve as foil to me while having no free will of your own. So I guess we're both unhappy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh fuck you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tune in next time for a proper technical blog post and more witty banter between me and an imaginary construct!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-11-29-this-is-a-blog-post/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-11-29-this-is-a-blog-post/
</link>
<title>
This is a blog post
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a blog post. The first in (hopefully) a series. A series of blog posts where I write about whatever is on my mind, probably mostly about computer stuff that I'm doing. An activity log, if you will. Maybe writing this is a way to organize my thoughts. Does it work? I don't know! I only just started. I also find that announcing out loud that I'm going to do  something severely decreases the chance of it ever getting done. Which is why I'm not going to say that I intend to write a blog post every other day. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But you just did!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I typed it. There's a difference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No there isn't. Announcing out loud and posting on a public website are just two different forms of the same action!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shut up Italics guy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, where was I? Oh yes, organizing my thoughts. This might be a good way to debrief what I've  learned. Also a good way to practice writing things out. This is an exercise for me (Lord knows I don't get enough of that).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that that's out of the way, lets address the elephant in the room. How the &lt;em&gt;hell&lt;/em&gt; did you get here? You, yes you, the reader. Let me assure you that there other way more interesting programmer blogs out there. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://steve-yegge.blogspot.com/'&gt;Steve Yegge&lt;/a&gt; (and his &lt;a href='https://sites.google.com/site/steveyegge2/blog-rants'&gt;old one&lt;/a&gt; too)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://jvns.ca/'&gt;Julia Evans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.codinghorror.com/'&gt;Coding Horror&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or just go visit reddit. Here's a &lt;a href='https://www.reddit.com/user/ashish2199/m/cs_student_subs/'&gt;multireddit&lt;/a&gt; to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's it for this time. Tune in next time for Subil's exciting adventures in Linux, or Lisp, or Python. Who knows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-10-01-dope-setup-no-code/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-10-01-dope-setup-no-code/
</link>
<title>
Your setup is dope, but where's your code?
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a problem. I have spent more time in the last month setting up and tinkering with an environment for me to code in than I have in actual coding. This is not a good thing,  especially for someone who is a total novice like I am who definitely needs to sharpen his skills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With studies and other stuff eating up most of my time, I have relatively little time to spend to do this thing that I love so much. And I genuinely do love to code. I need to use &lt;a href='http://www.workrave.org/'&gt;Workrave&lt;/a&gt; to unglue my eyes from the screen  from time to time. Sitting down to write a some program to solve some problem or do  some task is, for lack of a more fitting term, &lt;em&gt;amazeballs&lt;/em&gt;. The time I have is precious to me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what I actually end up doing a lot of the time is trying to customize my Vim environment, trying to find tools to code easier, or lint my code, or perform syntax checks, or contemplating dropping Vim altogether and adopt &lt;a href='http://spacemacs.org/'&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/a&gt; and start all over again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now I don't regret installing and configuring all the bells and whistles I have now  (&lt;a href='https://tmux.github.io/'&gt;Tmux&lt;/a&gt; especially is bloody brilliant!). But I think I could've spent that time  better. The time I spent reading about Spacemacs layers could have been better spent learning me some Clojure. The time I spent figuring how to auto lint my python code could've been by, y'know,  &lt;em&gt;actually writing&lt;/em&gt; the python code I so desperately want to lint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I'm done with the tinkering. I'm putting it to a complete stop because chasing that perfect environment is just a huge time sink that would've been for nothing if I find myself wanting to use something  else because it looks really cool (Have I mentioned &lt;a href='http://spacemacs.org/'&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/a&gt; yet?). I'm going to stick to my current toolbox until I actually have some code worthy of all the work I put into that setup. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This being my first blog ever (WOOHOO!). Here's an obligatory Hello World.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;python&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; print&amp;#40;&amp;quot;Hello, World!&amp;quot;&amp;#41;

# &amp;quot;Hello, World!&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
