<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:atom='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
<channel>
<atom:link href='http://dragsubil.github.io' rel='self' type='application/rss+xml'/>
<title>
(dragsubil's blog)
</title>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io
</link>
<description>
This might be a blog
</description>
<lastBuildDate>
Thu, 01 Dec 2016 19:52:24 +0530
</lastBuildDate>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-1-useless-blog-01/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-1-useless-blog-01/
</link>
<title>
Useless Blog #1
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh hey. You're back. I didn't think you'd write another post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yeah, well, I said I would, didn't I? So here I am. But it's not like I have  anything interesting to say though. I thought I would learn enough in two days to write something interesting. But the most interesting thing I did that I have any coherent thoughts about is that I shaved my head.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sigh&lt;/em&gt; I want to write but at the same time I don't want to fill this blog up with rambling crap (unless its entertaining crap). On the bright side, Christmas is only 25 days away (woo!). But college starts the day after (boo!). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had planned that this blog would be more of a stream of consciousness thing but that doesn't work really well if your stream of consciousness isn't very interesting. So for the next blog I'll least get a topic knocking around in my head before I sit down and write something. Hey, I'm actually starting to get ideas as I type this. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So are you going to rewrite this post?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No. I'm lazy. And this post isn't &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; bad. I'll leave it here. Like, y'know, legacy code!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But legacy code is generally not a good thing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And you're an imaginary rubber duck constructed and maintained by my mind to serve as foil to me while having no free will of your own. So I guess we're both unhappy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh fuck you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tune in next time for a proper technical blog post and more witty banter between me and an imaginary construct!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-11-29-this-is-a-blog-post/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-11-29-this-is-a-blog-post/
</link>
<title>
This is a blog post
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a blog post. The first in (hopefully) a series. A series of blog posts where I write about whatever is on my mind, probably mostly about computer stuff that I'm doing. An activity log, if you will. Maybe writing this is a way to organize my thoughts. Does it work? I don't know! I only just started. I also find that announcing out loud that I'm going to do  something severely decreases the chance of it ever getting done. Which is why I'm not going to say that I intend to write a blog post every other day. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But you just did!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I typed it. There's a difference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No there isn't. Announcing out loud and posting on a public website are just two different forms of the same action!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shut up Italics guy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, where was I? Oh yes, organizing my thoughts. This might be a good way to debrief what I've  learned. Also a good way to practice writing things out. This is an exercise for me (Lord knows I don't get enough of that).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that that's out of the way, lets address the elephant in the room. How the &lt;em&gt;hell&lt;/em&gt; did you get here? You, yes you, the reader. Let me assure you that there other way more interesting programmer blogs out there. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='ttp://steve-yegge.blogspot.com/'&gt;Steve Yegge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='ttp://jvns.ca/'&gt;Julia Evans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='ttps://blog.codinghorror.com/'&gt;Coding Horror&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or just go visit reddit. Here's a &lt;a href='ttps://www.reddit.com/user/ashish2199/m/cs_student_subs/'&gt;multireddit&lt;/a&gt; to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's it for this time. Tune in next time for Subil's exciting adventures in Linux, or Lisp, or Python. Who knows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-10-01-dope-setup-no-code/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-10-01-dope-setup-no-code/
</link>
<title>
Your setup is dope, but where's your code?
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a problem. I have spent more time in the last month setting up and tinkering with an environment for me to code in than I have in actual coding. This is not a good thing,  especially for someone who is a total novice like I am who definitely needs to sharpen his skills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With studies and other stuff eating up most of my time, I have relatively little time to spend to do this thing that I love so much. And I genuinely do love to code. I need to use &lt;a href='http://www.workrave.org/'&gt;Workrave&lt;/a&gt; to unglue my eyes from the screen  from time to time. Sitting down to write a some program to solve some problem or do  some task is, for lack of a more fitting term, &lt;em&gt;amazeballs&lt;/em&gt;. The time I have is precious to me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what I actually end up doing a lot of the time is trying to customize my Vim environment, trying to find tools to code easier, or lint my code, or perform syntax checks, or contemplating dropping Vim altogether and adopt &lt;a href='http://spacemacs.org/'&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/a&gt; and start all over again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now I don't regret installing and configuring all the bells and whistles I have now  (&lt;a href='https://tmux.github.io/'&gt;Tmux&lt;/a&gt; especially is bloody brilliant!). But I think I could've spent that time  better. The time I spent reading about Spacemacs layers could have been better spent learning me some Clojure. The time I spent figuring how to auto lint my python code could've been by, y'know,  &lt;em&gt;actually writing&lt;/em&gt; the python code I so desperately want to lint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I'm done with the tinkering. I'm putting it to a complete stop because chasing that perfect environment is just a huge time sink that would've been for nothing if I find myself wanting to use something  else because it looks really cool (Have I mentioned &lt;a href='http://spacemacs.org/'&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/a&gt; yet?). I'm going to stick to my current toolbox until I actually have some code worthy of all the work I put into that setup. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This being my first blog ever (WOOHOO!). Here's an obligatory Hello World.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;python&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; print&amp;#40;&amp;quot;Hello, World!&amp;quot;&amp;#41;

# &amp;quot;Hello, World!&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
