<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:atom='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
<channel>
<atom:link href='http://dragsubil.github.io' rel='self' type='application/rss+xml'/>
<title>
(dragsubil's blog)
</title>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io
</link>
<description>
This might be a blog
</description>
<lastBuildDate>
Thu, 08 Dec 2016 23:17:25 +0530
</lastBuildDate>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-07-the-monster-sneaks-up/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-07-the-monster-sneaks-up/
</link>
<title>
The monster that sneaks up on you
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I realize that the posting schedule has gone to whack but that last post was  too long to finish in one day. And so I decided I could skip a day as a reward (not that I dislike writing these, mind! But I didn't want to overextend myself). Also I realize this is not necessarily a technical post but it is something I need  to address, for my own sake. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was of the opinion that if you were aware of or had read about a situation before,  you could identify it immediately when it occurred to you and you could be prepared to handle it.  (This doesn't apply for every situation, of course. No amount of reading could suitably prepare you for, say, being dropped in front a herd of hungry velociraptors). Turns out I wasn't entirely right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's the holidays for me right now and a friend of mine invited me develop an Android app with him. I thought &quot;Hey! Why not!&quot; and said yes, despite knowing zilch about app development. I thought I could learn as I go along. This was a week ago and I haven't much much progress. Whereas my friend has already started work on the app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another friend of mine has started to learn Python. He'd been putting it off for quite a while but is now blazing through it. Far faster than my sorry ass did when I started (It took four years before I wrote my first Python application). This guy is also a Javascript ace, wrote a &lt;a href='http://babble.gq/'&gt;chat app&lt;/a&gt; that's actually been seen and appreciated by other people, and can pull all-nighters without turning into a zombie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And so the doubts started to creep in. &quot;Am I doing enough?&quot; &quot;Is there more I could be learning?&quot; &quot;Am I making the most of my day?&quot; and on and on. It wasn't just seeing my friends that brought this on. It's a whole host of things that builds up overtime. Seeing other people do cool shit while I sit here doing comparatively nothing. There are twelve year olds with a dozen apps  in the app stores and its not just their grandma who is using them. What the heck have I done with  my life? A couple of silly Python scripts? This dumb blog that a grand total of two people, including myself, read? What?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Say hello to the monster. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That feeling of inadequacy that every programmer goes through at least once in their lifetime. The feeling that everyone in this business is way smarter and more talented than you are. That no matter how much you try, how much you try to learn, you can never keep up with everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;...and that's okay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No, really! It's okay to feel that way. I'd read about it a lot and thought I was prepared. But it still caught me. It catches everyone. There's no escaping it. There's always going to be more to learn no matter how much you try. There's always going to be folks smarter than you. So don't stress yourself over what everyone else has done. Do what's best for you! Don't burn yourself out trying to do everything. Programming isn't  fun or productive if you don't allow yourself time to just chill out. If all you ever do is compete with everyone else over who has the most knowledge, or knows the most frameworks, or writes code in the  most languages, programming won't be fun anymore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heck! Don't take my word for it. I'm just some random bonehead who spends too much time on Reddit. Take &lt;a href='https://blog.codinghorror.com/keeping-up-and-just-in-time-learning/'&gt;Jeff Atwood's word&lt;/a&gt; instead. Or take the word of dozens of people who've talked about  &lt;a href='https://www.google.com/search?#hl=en&amp;q=imposter+syndrome'&gt;Imposter Syndrome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blog post is addressed from the me of the now to the me of the future (and also to my buddy the  Javascript ace, who tends to feel this way from time to time (Hey there pal!)). Because this probably won't be the last time you feel this way. We all feel inadequate sometimes, even the smartypants. That doesn't mean you're not doing enough. You're doing fine, mate! You're &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; doing comparatively nothing. You're doing a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; more than your than your stupid brain thinks. Just as long as you keep moving  forward and don't become complacent, that's plenty enough. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-04-ordovim/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-04-ordovim/
</link>
<title>
Ordovim or: How to half ass something with (predictably) crappy results
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; Neal Stephenson's books. He is the God Uncle of cyberpunk (the God&lt;em&gt;father&lt;/em&gt; of cyberpunk is, of course, William Gibson). One of Stephenson's doorstoppers is Cryptonomicon, a MASSIVE, 1100+ page monstrosity jam packed with everything you could want in a historical fiction/sorta cyberpunk novel. It's got action, World War II code breaking, guest appearances by Alan Turing, digressions on cryptography, a few predictions about the future (internet banking being one of them. Remember, it was published in 1999) and a ton of other things I can't remember. It even had graphs. &lt;em&gt;GRAPHS&lt;/em&gt; for duck's sake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, one of the things I remembered reading about in the book is Ordoemacs. Ordoemacs is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; text editor for the paranoid. Everything written in Ordoemacs is automatically encrypted when written to disk. At least, that's how I remembered it. So I wanted to do something similar, but in Vim. Thus, Ordovim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(See that 'half ass' in the title? Start counting them).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing a text editor from scratch is hard, really hard. Especially one with as much power as Vim. So I chose not to bother. A Vim plugin would've been easier. (This was my first, but understandable and sane, half ass. I'm nothing if not pragmatic).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;But I have to learn Vimscript to write a plugin. And Vimscript is &lt;em&gt;stoopid&lt;/em&gt;! Ugh!&quot;, I whined internally. Vimscript is powerful, no doubt! I mean, just look at all the &lt;a href='http://vimawesome.com/'&gt;plugins&lt;/a&gt; available. They're pretty rad. But my lazy bum didn't want to take the time to sit down and fully learn this kinda ugly language (&lt;a href='http://spacemacs.org/'&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/a&gt; and Elisp's distant siren song isn't helping either). So I decided to learn just enough to help me write this thing. But I soon found out plugins require a greater investment in time and learning  than I was inclined to give. So I reduced the requirement from a plugin to a function and a couple of autocommands. (This was my second half ass. Seeing a trend?).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;But you couldn't possibly do proper encryption with a single function.&quot; I hear you say. And you're right. Also I knew diddly squat about cryptography. Still don't, unless you call importing and using a Python library as sufficient cryptographic expertise. And that's exactly what I did. &lt;a href='https://github.com/andrewcooke/simple-crypt'&gt;Simple Crypt&lt;/a&gt; is a wrapper around a much more complex and powerful Python library called &lt;a href='https://www.dlitz.net/software/pycrypto/'&gt;PyCrypto&lt;/a&gt;. It's a kiddie fence created to protect knuckleheads like me from hurting myself trying  to climb the metaphorical jungle gym. It is dead simple to use. And gave me an easy way out from having to actually learn some cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;python&quot;&gt;from simplecrypt import encrypt, decrypt

plain&amp;#95;string = &amp;quot;This do be a string. Fortune prick me if it is not&amp;quot;
password = &amp;quot;yourpassword&amp;quot;

encrypted&amp;#95;string = encrypt&amp;#40;password, plain&amp;#95;string.encode&amp;#40;'UTF-8'&amp;#41;&amp;#41;
decrypted&amp;#95;string = decrypt&amp;#40;password, encrypted&amp;#95;string.decode&amp;#40;'UTF-8'&amp;#41;&amp;#41;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is literally that easy to use. I needed to do nothing else. Ask me what SHA1 stands for and you'll just get a blank stare. I wrote a dead simple python script with an easy to use encryption library and added a few lines to my vimrc to call that script whenever I opened a file with the extension &lt;code&gt;.ordo.enc&lt;/code&gt; (to decrypt it) or closed a file with the extension &lt;code&gt;.ordo&lt;/code&gt; (to encrypt it). (Half ass numero très).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The end result? It's... working? Sort of? Opening an encrypted file automatically decrypts it. But half asses strike back! You can't close the file or delete the buffer and expect that it will encrypt. Whichever buffer your '*.ordo' file is, only the file in the current buffer gets encrypted. You have to switch to the buffer of the file you want to encrypt before closing it. But hey! It's working. Right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Well that was a fun project!&quot;, I thought in my elation upon completion. &quot;Not half bad!&quot; You know how children can sit in a cardboard box and pretend they're piloting a spaceship. That was me, thinking I'd just made a working clone of Ordoemacs with some tape and a couple of screws. A true MacGyver is me. And so in the spirit of things, I decided to read that part in Cryptonomicon where they talk about Ordoemacs again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recall that I mentioned at the beginning this phrase: 'Alteast, that's how I &lt;em&gt;remembered&lt;/em&gt; it.' See that added emphasis on 'remembered'? Yeah. I've been going by memory all this time about how Ordoemacs actually worked. I hadn't opened that book in quite a while. Here's the quote from the book:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; OrdoEmacs, on the other hand, works exactly like regular Emacs, except that it encrypts everything before writing it out to disk. At no time is plaintext ever laid down on a disk by OrdoEmacs&amp;ndash;the only place it exists in its plain, readable form is in the pixels on the screen, and in the volatile RAM of the computer, whence it vanishes the moment power is shut down. Not only that, but it's coupled to a screensaver that uses the little built-in CCD camera in the laptop to check to see if you are actually there. It can't recognize your face, but it can tell whether or not a vaguely human-shaped form is sitting in front of it, and if that vaguely human-shaped form goes away, even for a fraction of a second, it will drop into a screen-saver that will blank the display and freeze the machine until such time as you type in a password, or biometrically verify your identity through voice recognition. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's.. well.. that's definitely not what I created.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here was my biggest half ass of them all. My halfiest ass, if you will. I never bothered to look at what Ordoemacs actually did before I set out to write &quot;Ordovim&quot;. Let's look at them one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; the only place it exists in its plain, readable form is in the pixels on the screen, and in the volatile RAM of the computer &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yeah, no. My &quot;Ordovim&quot; actually writes to disc first before encrypting and deleting the old plaintext file (which can easily be recovered).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; coupled to a screensaver &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; uses the little built-in CCD camera in the laptop to check to see if you are actually there &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; blank the display and freeze the machine until such time as you type in a password, or biometrically verify your identity through voice recognition. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nopity nopity nope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Ordovim&quot;, besides the fact that it does encryption, isn't even in the same galaxy as Ordoemacs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what was the takeaway here? Some of the things I learned at the end of this ordeal, which should be obvious to anyone with three quarters of a brain:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don't half ass things, because half asses multiply (I'm at sixteenth ass now).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Read the spec or you end up with &quot;Ordovim&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Invest a little bit of time to learning how to use and improve your skills with your tools (even if you think they are 'stoopid').&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Kiddie fences are nice, but you have to grow up sometime.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh! And go read Neal Stephenson books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find Ordovim &lt;a href='https://github.com/dragsubil/Ordovim'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Sun, 04 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-01-useless-blog-01/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-12-01-useless-blog-01/
</link>
<title>
Useless Blog #1
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh hey. You're back. I didn't think you'd write another post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yeah, well, I said I would, didn't I? So here I am. But it's not like I have  anything interesting to say though. I thought I would learn enough in two days to write something interesting. But the most interesting thing I did that I have any coherent thoughts about is that I shaved my head.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sigh&lt;/em&gt; I want to write but at the same time I don't want to fill this blog up with rambling crap (unless its entertaining crap). On the bright side, Christmas is only 25 days away (woo!). But college starts the day after (boo!). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had planned that this blog would be more of a stream of consciousness thing but that doesn't work really well if your stream of consciousness isn't very interesting. So for the next blog I'll least get a topic knocking around in my head before I sit down and write something. Hey, I'm actually starting to get ideas as I type this. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So are you going to rewrite this post?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No. I'm lazy. And this post isn't &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; bad. I'll leave it here. Like, y'know, legacy code!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But legacy code is generally not a good thing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And you're an imaginary rubber duck constructed and maintained by my mind to serve as foil to me while having no free will of your own. So I guess we're both unhappy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh fuck you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tune in next time for a proper technical blog post and more witty banter between me and an imaginary construct!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-11-29-this-is-a-blog-post/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-11-29-this-is-a-blog-post/
</link>
<title>
This is a blog post
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a blog post. The first in (hopefully) a series. A series of blog posts where I write about whatever is on my mind, probably mostly about computer stuff that I'm doing. An activity log, if you will. Maybe writing this is a way to organize my thoughts. Does it work? I don't know! I only just started. I also find that announcing out loud that I'm going to do  something severely decreases the chance of it ever getting done. Which is why I'm not going to say that I intend to write a blog post every other day. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But you just did!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I typed it. There's a difference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No there isn't. Announcing out loud and posting on a public website are just two different forms of the same action!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shut up Italics guy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, where was I? Oh yes, organizing my thoughts. This might be a good way to debrief what I've  learned. Also a good way to practice writing things out. This is an exercise for me (Lord knows I don't get enough of that).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that that's out of the way, lets address the elephant in the room. How the &lt;em&gt;hell&lt;/em&gt; did you get here? You, yes you, the reader. Let me assure you that there other way more interesting programmer blogs out there. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://steve-yegge.blogspot.com/'&gt;Steve Yegge&lt;/a&gt; (and his &lt;a href='https://sites.google.com/site/steveyegge2/blog-rants'&gt;old one&lt;/a&gt; too)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://jvns.ca/'&gt;Julia Evans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.codinghorror.com/'&gt;Coding Horror&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or just go visit reddit. Here's a &lt;a href='https://www.reddit.com/user/ashish2199/m/cs_student_subs/'&gt;multireddit&lt;/a&gt; to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's it for this time. Tune in next time for Subil's exciting adventures in Linux, or Lisp, or Python. Who knows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<guid>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-10-01-dope-setup-no-code/
</guid>
<link>
http://dragsubil.github.io/posts/2016-10-01-dope-setup-no-code/
</link>
<title>
Your setup is dope, but where's your code?
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a problem. I have spent more time in the last month setting up and tinkering with an environment for me to code in than I have in actual coding. This is not a good thing,  especially for someone who is a total novice like I am who definitely needs to sharpen his skills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With studies and other stuff eating up most of my time, I have relatively little time to spend to do this thing that I love so much. And I genuinely do love to code. I need to use &lt;a href='http://www.workrave.org/'&gt;Workrave&lt;/a&gt; to unglue my eyes from the screen  from time to time. Sitting down to write a some program to solve some problem or do  some task is, for lack of a more fitting term, &lt;em&gt;amazeballs&lt;/em&gt;. The time I have is precious to me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what I actually end up doing a lot of the time is trying to customize my Vim environment, trying to find tools to code easier, or lint my code, or perform syntax checks, or contemplating dropping Vim altogether and adopt &lt;a href='http://spacemacs.org/'&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/a&gt; and start all over again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now I don't regret installing and configuring all the bells and whistles I have now  (&lt;a href='https://tmux.github.io/'&gt;Tmux&lt;/a&gt; especially is bloody brilliant!). But I think I could've spent that time  better. The time I spent reading about Spacemacs layers could have been better spent learning me some Clojure. The time I spent figuring how to auto lint my python code could've been by, y'know,  &lt;em&gt;actually writing&lt;/em&gt; the python code I so desperately want to lint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I'm done with the tinkering. I'm putting it to a complete stop because chasing that perfect environment is just a huge time sink that would've been for nothing if I find myself wanting to use something  else because it looks really cool (Have I mentioned &lt;a href='http://spacemacs.org/'&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/a&gt; yet?). I'm going to stick to my current toolbox until I actually have some code worthy of all the work I put into that setup. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This being my first blog ever (WOOHOO!). Here's an obligatory Hello World.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;python&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; print&amp;#40;&amp;quot;Hello, World!&amp;quot;&amp;#41;

# &amp;quot;Hello, World!&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
<enclosure>

</enclosure>
<pubDate>
Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0530
</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
